# **Oniel Santos**

Full-Stack Developer

Santiago, Dominican Republic (GMT-4)

contact@onielsantos.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/onielsantos

https://github.com/Oniel1721

Full-Stack developer with more than 3 years of experience with **JavaScript & NodeJs**. Experienced developing software in the Healthcare industry. Love teaching new talents and helping them grow professionally. Wish to lead teams with impact around the world. Looking to work in teams where I help others grow with me.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Vertrical Inc** — January 2023 - Present

**Senior Software Engineer** — January2023 - Present

- Satisfied 100% of stakeholders developing features such as **orders**, **payment** and **fulfillment**.
- Improved user experience by 90% solving high priority bugs.
- Increased security by 90% following standards such as HIPAA and GDPR.
- Accelerated development experience by 200% creating automatization tools.

Tech Stack: NextJs, NestJs, AWS, Stripe, Docker, TypeScript.

#### Intellisys D. Corp, VacunateRD — April 2021 - December 2022

Mid-Level Full-stack Developer — March 2022 - December 2022

- Accelerated delivery speed by 85% by leading a team of interns and juniors on an internal project.
- Improved by 90% code maintainability through code review and by implementing clean code designs.

**Tech Stack:** NestJs, Nextjs, TypeScript, PostgreSQL & Docker.

## Junior Full-stack Developer — July 2021 - February 2022

- Improved by 500% the COVID-19 vaccination registration process to +10M people by leading a team of +5 developers.
- Reduced errors by 85% by implementing unit testing and end-to-end testing.
- Improved by 90% web security by using Response Headers.
- Increased request speed by 400% by using ElasticSearch for rapid access to data.

**Tech Stack:** NestJs, ExpressJs, Strapi, React, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch & Docker.

## Programming Internship — April 2021 - June 2021

Improved the UI of the app by 50% using React and Material UI.

Tech Stack: React and Material UI.

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

## **Cincinnatus Institute of Craftsmanship** — September 2021 - Present

#### **Technical Coach & Evaluator**

- Improved by 50% the learning path experience by looking for modern and free alternatives for courses.
- Reduced the learning curve by 200% for my students through coaching and training sessions.
- Impacted 80% of students through talks on software development and programming.
- Helped improve programming skills by 90% by giving feedback on projects and teaching students.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Git, Github.

## **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Dart.

Frameworks Tools: NodeJs, NestJs, Express, React, NextJs, Django, SvelteKit, Flutter.

Cloud & Data Base: AWS, S3, IAM, EC2, Lambda, DynamoDB, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, ElasticSearch, Redis.

**Tools:** Docker, Git, GitHub, GitHub Actions, Figma, Stripe.

Agile: Scrum, Kanban.

Languages: English, Spanish.

## **EDUCATION**

**Self-taught** – Youtube, Platzi, Udemy, Personal projects, and other sources every day since 2019. **Cincinnatus Institute of Craftsmanship** – Software Craftsman's Apprentice, November 2021 **Infotep** – Web Designer CSS and JavaScript, April 2020.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

NextJs: React Framework for Production - Udemy. 2022.

Platzi: AWS Cloud Practitioner - Platzi. 2023.